Dunham Family Papers, 1814-1951
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr. (1901-1951)
  - Activities, general
    - Seal Harbor Committee for Fire Protection
      - Maps of Seal Harbor with fire lines drawn in, ca. 1930 (Box 30)
        [see Oversize materials, Flat file]
      - Lists of expenses, receipts, 1930-31, undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Mount Desert Island Hospital
      - Building committee: correspondence, minutes, 1937-38 (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Executive committee
        - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 10)
        - Reports, notes, 1946-47, undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Mount Desert Island High School
      - Correspondence, 1948-49 (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Reports, printed material, 1948-49 (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Clippings, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Mount Desert Island Harbor Project
      - Correspondence, 1938-40, undated (Box 31, Folder 1-3)
      - Reports, printed material, clippings, 1938-39 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Church organ committee (Seal Harbor): correspondence, brochures, 1949, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Hancock County Trustees of Public Reservation: "Historical sketch: 1901-1933 " (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Mount Desert Island Authority Plan: correspondence, 1935-36 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Clear Pool Camp: correspondence, minutes, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Seal Harbor Yacht Club: correspondence, financial statements, 1925, 1930, 1945-48 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Yacht - building & repairs: correspondence, notes, 1922-35, undated (Box 31, Folder 10-11)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, printed material, 1923, 1937-38, undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Financial
    - Leases, 1934-35, 1941-42 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Receipts, miscellaneous correspondence, 1933, 1941, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Memorabilia
    - Writings (by others), 1918, 1925, 1938-39, undated (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Nurse's pneumonia chart for EKD, 1928, 1931 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Invitations, miscellaneous memorabilia, 1918, 1932-34, 1938, undated (includes photos) (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Clippings, 1911, 1925, 1927-28, 1931, 1933, 1935, 1939, undated (Box 31, Folder 18)
- Nancy (Yellott) Dunham (dates unknown)
  - Correspondence
    - Mary (Dows) Dunham, 1933-35, undated (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - General, 1933, 1935, 1939-40, 1942, undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - List of condolence writers to NYD on death of EKD, Jr. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Condolence letters on EKD, Jr's death, A-Z, 1951-52 (Box 32, Folder 5-10)
    - NYD's answers to condolence letters - drafts, notes, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - NYD to Mary Yellott, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Activities
    - The Hardy Garden Club: correspondence, printed material, 1937, 1940, undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Memorabilia
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1933, undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Edward K. Dunham, III (1935- ): correspondence, 1949, undated (Box 32, Folder 16)
- PHOTOGRAPHS
  [see also Oversize materials and the Bodman Family Papers]
  Note: Some photographs are filed with the papers if their subject content is specifically related to that material.
  - Family and friends, ca. 1890-1930 (Box 33)
  - Individuals, A-Z
    - Groups (Box 33)
    - Unidentified people (Box 33)
  - Seal Harbor (Me.), ca. 1920-30 (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Cromwell Hall, Ct. (Box 33)
    - Dogs (Box 33)
    - Forts (Box 33)
    - Unidentified scenes (Box 33)
  - Oversize photographs
    - Family and friends, A-Z, 1877, 1883, 1897, 1928, undated (Box 34, Folder 1-6)
    - Unidentified people, undated [could be Bodman family] (Box 34, Folder 6b)
    - Miscellaneous: Boats, dogs, horses, 1905, 1911, 1922-23, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr.: photograph album, ca. 1910-20 (Box 34)
    - Mary (Dows) and Edward Kellogg Dunham, Sr.
      - Egypt, 1906-07 (Box 35)
      - England, ca. 1890s (Box 36)
      - France, ca. 1890s (Box 36)
      - Italy, ca. 1890s (Box 36)
      - Switzerland, ca. 1890s (Box 36)
      - Unidentified (Europe), ca. 1890s (Box 36)
      - Oversize photographs, including contact prints made May 1993 from original negatives
        - Greece, 1914, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
        - Italy, ca. 1890s, 1907-14 (Box 37, Folder 2-5)
        - Switzerland, Holland, France, ca. 1890s (Box 37, Folder 6)
        - Unidentified (Europe), ca. 1907-1914 (Box 38, Folder 1)
        - Egypt, 1906-07 (Box 38, Folder 2-3)
      - Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr.
        - Western U.S., Panama, ca. 1930-31 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Postcards: Egypt, England, Italy, undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Albums and scrapbooks
        - Europe, mostly Italy, ca. 1890s? (Box 39)
        - Egypt, 1906-07, [see also box 57] (Box 40)
        - Europe, 1910 (Box 40)
        - France (mostly postcards), ca. 1910-14 (Box 40)
- NEGATIVES
  - Mary (Dows) and Edward Kellogg Dunham, Sr.
    - Glass plate negatives
      [see contact prints in Photographs: Family and friends, boxes 33 and 34]
      - Theodora (Dunham) Bodman, 1897 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - "Tom and Kit before buckboard," 1883 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Unidentified people, undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Cemeteries, 1922, 1924, 1927-28, undated (Box 42)
    - Greece, 1914 (Box 42)
    - Italy, ca. 1890s, 1907, 1910-14 (Box 42)
    - Switzerland, ca. 1890s (Box 42)
    - Egypt, 1906-07 (Box 43)
  - Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr.
    - Family, ca. 1910-1931, undated
      - Individuals, A-Z 1910-1931, undated (Box 44)
      - Groups (Box 44)
    - Friends, ca. 1920-1932, undated
      - Individuals, A-Z 1920-1932, undated (Box 45)
      - Groups 1920-1932, undated (Box 46)
    - Unidentified people 1920-1932, undated (Box 47)
    - Mount Desert Island, 1910-38, undated
      - Scenic views 1910-38, undated (Box 48)
      - Seal Harbor Village Improvement Society (Box 48)
      - Other Seal Harbor activities (Box 48)
      - Northeast coast (not Mount Desert Island), ca. 1919-32, 1910-38, undated (Box 49)
      - Europe, Mediterranean, Egypt, 1923 1910-38, undated (Box 50)
      - Caribbean 1927 1910-38, undated (Box 51)
      - Panama, 1928-30 (Box 51)
      - Western United States, ca. 1927-32, undated
        - Arizona 1927-32, undated (Box 52)
        - California, New Mexico, Texas, Wyoming, unidentified scenery 1927-32, undated (Box 53)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Cemeteries, 1922, 1924, 1927-28 (Box 54)
        - Boats, ca. 1920-32, undated (Box 54)
        - Dogs, 1924, 1926, 1931, undated (Box 54)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Mary (Dows) Dunham
    - Artwork - Stencils, sketches, watercolors, 1883-84 (Box 55)
    - Oversize photographs
      [see also Photographs, box 33-39]
      - Greece, ca. 1914 (Box 55)
      - "Belfast, ME" by C. A. Townsend, undated (Box 55)
  - Carroll Dunham, Sr
    - Scrapbook of correspondence and receipts, 1788, ca. 1841-1875 (Box 56)
    - Memorial scroll - "Resolutions on the death of Carroll Dunham," 1877 (Box 56)
  - Carroll and Harriet (Kellogg) Dunham
    - 3 scrapbooks of correspondence and writings (inc. letters from Elizabeth Barrett Browning, Samuel Longfellow, Lucy Stone, Zachary Taylor), ca. 1850-70s (Box 56)
      [see also Carroll Dunham, Sr., box 41 and Harriet (Kellogg) Dunham, box 7]
  - David Dows
    - Memorial scrapbook - clippings, family histories, correspondence, photographs, ca. 1890, undated (Box 56)
  - David and Margaret (Worcester) Dows
    - Silver wedding anniversary album (includes family photographs), 1877 (Box 56)
      [see also Dows Family, box 16]
  - Mary Dows Dunham: Photograph album by of trip to Egypt, 1906 (Box 57)
  - Dunham Family Photograph album, Seal Harbor, 1910s-20s (Box 58)
  - Mary (Dows) and Edward Kellogg Dunham, Sr.
    - Floor plans for 35 East 68th Street, New York (N.Y.) and "Keewaydin," Seal Harbor (Me.), undated (Map-case Flat file)
    - Designs from Tiffany Studios, NYC:
      - 1. Sketches of chair and table, undated (Map-case Flat file)
      - 2. Watercolor of "suggestion for tapestry from hall to library" (Map-case Flat file)
  - Dunham, Kellogg and Dows families
    - Cemetery maps, headstone drawings and headstone rubbing [for Harriet (Kellogg) Dunham], undated (Map-case Flat file)
      [see also General Family Histories, box 1]
  - Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr.
    - Seal Harbor Committee for Fire Protection: maps of Seal Harbor (Me.) with fire lines drawn in, ca. 1930 (Map-case Flat file)
      [see also Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr., box 30]